### **DUNCAN J. MAYER**

### DATA SCIENTIST | SOCIAL SCIENTIST | HEALTH SCIENTIST

DuncanMayer77@gmail.com · Personal Website · Github · LinkedIn · ORCID

### **SUMMARY**

I am a scientist with nearly a decade of experience using data to predict and understand complex behavior and phenomenon. I maintain good coding practices and am comfortable building, evaluating, and interpreting everything from well known algorithms to bespoke models. In addition to my methodological expertise, I bring domain expertise in organizational theory, neighborhood effects, as well as program and policy evaluation. I have produced research for a range of audiences including academic, government, and private sector stakeholders. You can find my full academic CV here.

**PROGRAMMING:** R (8 years) | SQL (4 years) | Stan (3 years) | Python (1 year)

STATISTICS: Hierarchical Models | Spatial Statistics | Longitudinal Data Analysis | Machine Learning | Experimentation

### **EDUCATION**

Case Western Reserve University

Cleveland, OH (Expected August) 2023

PhD in Social Welfare

(Expected August) 2023

Marywood University Masters of Social Work Bachelors of Social Work

2017 2015

Scranton, PA

### RECENT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**BeVera Solutions** 

Atlanta, GA

Health Statistician (full-time)

Sept. 2022 – Present

• Led all statistical aspects of four white papers for the National Center for Infectious and Respiratory Disease focused on improving health sciences and evaluating the nation's COVID-19 response within federal agencies

### **Case Western Reserve University**

Cleveland, OH

Research Fellow (full-time)

Aug. 2018 - June. 2022

- Led and managed all aspects of multiple scientific studies, publishing first and solo author papers including novel methodologies and state of the art applications.
- Provided methodological support and consultation for select research projects, affiliated with the The Center on Poverty and Community Development.
- Communicated methods and insights in over 5 technical talks at scientific conferences and over 150 hours of course lectures

## The Institute for Public Policy and Economic Development

Wilkes-Barre, PA

Development

Research Analyst (full-time)

July 2017 – June 2018

- Co-authored 11 funded research papers on a range of policy issues including health equity, health literacy, civic participation, and human services, leading data analysis in 5.
- Provided ad hoc data analysis to a variety government and corporate stakeholders

### **SELECT PAPERS**

### Simmer Down Now! A Study of Revenue Volatility and Dissolution in Nonprofit Organizations

• Quantified the effect of revenue volatility on dissolution in nonprofit organizations using archival tax records organizations (N = 2,126,894) and discrete time survival models (R,SQL)

# Can a Measurement Error Perspective Improve Estimation in Neighborhood Effects Research? A Hierarchical Bayesian Methodology

• Developed a probabilistic model to incorporate sampling error into neighborhoods effects research using a full Bayesian Methodology (Stan, R)

### Understanding Location and Density: A Spatial Analysis of Cuyahoga County's Nonprofit Sector

• Quantified the effects of location of nonprofit revenue using penalized spines (generalized additive models) showing the "best" locations are central in agglomeration clusters (R)